# C. Carlo Fazioli

Vienna VA
☐ 626.298.1212
☑ cfazzy@gmail.com

I am an applied mathematician and software engineering generalist with experience in cloud computing, AI, and DevOps. I am a lifelong learner with far-ranging interests, confident in my ability to rapidly spin up in new environments, as well as deep-dive into the gritty details.

# Current Position

# 2018 - 2024 Software Engineer, Group W, Inc, Vienna VA

Product manager of, and contributor to, an AI wargaming application developed as a multi-year, multimillion-dollar Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency seedling project between 2019-2021 before transitioning to further development under the Air Force Research Laboratory. Project was awarded the 2021 Military Operations Research Society Barchi prize.

#### O Product management:

- Iterated frequently with client-side management and SMEs to understand evolving priorities.
- Coordinated with client and developers to produce task orders and accurate level-ofeffort estimates.
- Communicated with corporate admins to track budget use.
- Authored monthly status reports and annual final reports.
- Presented at conferences and during networking calls to spread awareness of team efforts.

#### Cloud-native Architecture:

- Architected microservices and their interfaces.
- Designed two deployment mechanisms: Kubernetes and Docker.
- Managed Kubernetes objects using Helm.
- Defined cloud resource requirements with Infrastructure as Code.

### Agile Development:

- Acted as unofficial Agile Team Leader for a team of 10.
- Assembled a robust GitLab CICD Pipeline.
- Facilitated uniform development workflows with a custom Docker image.

## Software Engineering:

- Designed Al algorithms under a senior staff guidance.
- Implemented a from-scratch K-medoids algorithm to cluster wargame state data.
- Authored application source code in Python.
- Detailed significant portions of the project in technical documentation.
- Constructed a REST API and Software Development Kit.

#### System Administration:

- Controlled application access using Azure AD for corporate users, and Keycloak for external users
- Administrated multiple MongoDB instances (each 10GB-1TB)

# Education

2005 – 2009 Ph.D. Mathematics, University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago IL

2000 – 2004 B.S. Mathematics, University of San Francisco, San Francisco CA

# Previous Positions

2016 – 2018 Econometric Modeler, International Monetary Fund, Washington DC

Collaborated with IMF economists on global economic model development; researched, designed, and implemented algorithms for use by IMF staff; pursued exploratory research into technology solutions for IMF institutional needs; addressed technical needs of individual IMF staff.

2013 – 2016 **Assistant Teaching Professor**, *Dept. of Mathematics*, Drexel University, Philadelphia, PA

Developed course and lab materials; lectured, graded exams, monitored students' use of online resources, assigned final grades; assisted students as needed outside of class or in office hours; directed teaching assistants.

2011 – 2013 **Postdoctoral Research Associate**, *Dept. of Mathematical Sciences*, New Jersey Inst. of Tech., Newark, NJ

Researched, designed, and coded novel algorithms for use in fluid dynamics simulations; briefed research supervisor; presented findings to collaborators and conference attendees.

## Hobbies and Interests

- Solving the NYT crossword puzzle daily: I am on 401 day streak at the time of this writing!
- O Mindfullness: striving frequent meditator and proponent of mental health.
- Science fiction lit/TV/movies: I'm a fan of classic authors such as Phil K. Dick, contemporary authors such as Neal Stephenson, and the '80s and '90s campiness of movie director Paul Verhoeven.
- Ocoding competitions: I made it onto the 2021 Advent of Code global leaderboard!
- Cybersecurity: Avid listener of Risky Biz and Darknet Diaries podcasts; amateur malware analyst.